Dagwon
다그온
Yuusha Shirei
용자지령
Brave Command Dagwon
켄타!
Kenta!
어이! 기다려!
Hey! Wait for me!
자, 돌아가자!
Now, let's go back.
왜 그래, 켄타?
What's wrong, Kenta?
수정 눈동자 소년
The Boy with Crystal Eyes
전편
First Part
배달왔습니다!
Delivery!
네!
Sure!
-여어, 게키!
-받아.
-Hey, Geki!
-Here.
수고했어.
Thank you.
미성년자에게 팔았다는 거 들키면 난 모가지라구.
I'll be fired if someone finds out that I sold to a minor!
소심하게 그게 무슨 말입니까? 게키답지 않네요.
You look timid, and that's totally not like you.
뭬야?
What?!
전 지금 하고 있는 실험이 들키면 감옥 가는데요!
I'll be jailed if someone finds out about my experiment.
이자식, 날 범죄에 휘말리게 할 셈이냐?!
You bastard! Are you going to get me involved in a crime?!
여어, 아저씨! 뭐하고 있어?
Hey, uncle! What'cha doin'?
누, 누가 아저씨냐?! 성실한 근로 청년이란 말이다!
Wh- who are you calling "uncle"?! I am a faithful young working boy!
심부름 가시나요, 엔?
Are you going on an errand, En?
비디오 돌려주러 가는 길이야!
I'm going to return this video.
나중에 보자!
See ya!
흥, 어차피 지루한 애니메이션이나 본 거겠지.
Hmph, he must be watching some boring animations!
위험하잖냐!
That was dangerous!
왜 그래?
What's wrong?
너…
You…
이봐, 기다려!
Hey, wait!
너, 이름이 뭐야?
What's your name?
이름 말이야, 이름.
It's your name, your name.
이름…
Name…
그래, 난 엔.
Yes. I am En.
다이도우지 엔이야.
En Daidouji.
켄타…
Kenta.
나… 켄타.
I… Kenta.
정말 켄타야?
Is it really Kenta?
너, 쫓기고 있어?
Are you being chased?
아까 그 남자, 누구야?
Who was that man before?
이런 곳에 있었구만.
You were here?
아빠랑 돌아가자.
Let's go back with your dad.
자, 이리와.
Now, come here.
당신, 이 애의 아버지로는 안 보이는데?
You don't look like this boy's father.
꺼져.
Move.
흥, 싫은걸?
Hmph, no way!
튀자!
Come!
날아가자!
Let's fly!
갑자기 그런…! 취소라니!
That's so sudden! You're cancelling now?
그게 아니야!
That's not it!
그치만 말이야...
But…
아악, 잠깐 기다려! 에리카!
Hey, wait a moment! Erika!
이봐, 밥 먹자구.
Everyone, time for lunch!
네.
Right.
엔?
En?
또 미나코가 직접 만든 거구만.
I guess Minako made this for you again?
이거 먹을게.
I'll have one!
왜 그래?
What?
나 참, 못 써먹겠구만.
What should we do now?
그치만 그 옷차림, 어떻게든 해야 되는데…
Anyway, you should change your clothes…
잠깐 기다려.
Just a moment.
속옷 도둑, 퇴산(退散)!
Begone, underwear thief!
엔?
En?
가쿠의 옷이 딱 맞아서 다행이야.
What a relief! Gaku's clothes fit perfectly!
다행은 쥐뿔이 다행이냐.
What's so perfect?!
-자업자득이잖아!
-있으면 빨랑빨랑 튀어나오라구!
-You asked for it!
-If you were here, then you could have come out right away!
샤워중이라 어쩔 수 없었어!
It was because I was taking a shower!
그건 그렇고… 이 애, 어떻게 할 거야?
Anyway, what are you going to do with this kid?
어떻게 하냐니… 경찰서에라도 데려다 줘야지.
What should I do? I should take him to the police…
그건 위험할지도 몰라.
That might be dangerous.
경찰에도 손이 뻗혀 있을 가능성이 있어.
It's possible that the police are already involved.
그건 또 뭔 소리냐?
What's that now?
어쩌면… 이 애, 현대의 카스파 하우저일지도 몰라.
Maybe this boy can be the contemporary Kaspar Hauser.
(캇파: 河童, 물 속에 산다는 어린애 모양을 한 상상의 동물)
(Kappa: 河童, mythical water-dwelling young creature)
카, 캇파 수행자?!
A Ka- Kappa Trainee?!
너 귀가 어떻게 됐니?! 카·스·파·하·우·저!
Are your ears defunct? Kaspar Hauser!
그딴 놈, 알게 뭐야!
Like hell I know!
1928년의 어느날 독일 뉘른베르크의 길가에 갑자기 한 소년이 나타났다.
One day in 1928, a boy suddenly appeared on the street of Nuremberg in Germany.
신원도 과거도 모두 불명. 그 소년의 이름이 카스파 하우저.
Neither his identity nor past were known. The name of that boy is Kasper Hauser.
-그놈이 어쨌길래?
-일설에 의하면...
-So he's what?
-According to one theory,
그는 귀족의 집안 싸움 도중에 유괴되어 그 후로 17년간 어딘가에 감금되어 있었다고 해.
he was kidnapped during a family fight between two aristocrats, and imprisoned somewhere for 17 years.
-아아, 그래서?
-어떻게 도망치긴 했는데.
-And?
-He somehow ran away, but
콜로시아에게 몇번이고 노려져 결국 암살당했어.
Colossia continued to target him, until he finally was murdered.
어때, 이 애와 똑같지?
You see? It's just like this boy!
그럼 뭐시냐… 켄타는 어딘가의 도련님인데 유산 싸움인가 뭔가에 휘말렸다는 거야?
So that'd mean Kenta is a young gentlemen of some aristocrat, but he was involved in a fight for inheritance?
틀림없어.
No doubt about it.
켄타, 그런 거야?
Kenta, is that true?
너, 부잣집 도련님이야?
Are you a young nobleman of the rich?
도련님…
Young nobleman…
이거 곤란하구만.
This'll be troublesome.
너희집에 데려가지 그래?
Why not take him to your house?
그치만, 우리집은 미유키 녀석이 시끄러워서 말이야.
But Miyuki is already being noisy in my house.
카이네 집에 가서 상담해 봐야겠다.
I'll talk with Kai in his home.
그럼, 안녕.
See ya.
잠깐, 미유키가 누구야?!
Wait! Who's Miyuki?!
나기사! 어디 가는 거냐?!
Nagisa! Where are you going?
전부터 말하려고 했는데.
I was going to tell you before about…
너의 그 문란한 복장!
…your disorderly dress!
참으로 내 동생으로선 있을 수 없는…
That is unacceptable for my young sister!
여봐, 카이!
Hey, Kai!
안녕!
Heya!
-무슨 일이냐?
-아, 아니, 그…
-What are you doing here?
-Uh, that is…
조금 귀찮은 일이 생겨서 너와 상담하려고 말이야.
I think I got in trouble, so I'm here to talk with you about it.
엔, 지금이 몇월이지?
En, what month is it now?
몇월이냐니, 9월 아니야?
Isn't it September?
그 말대로다! 운명의 기로인 여름이 지나고 이제부터가 수험 공부의 절정!
That's right! The fate of summer is over, and now is the peak of the entrance exam preparation!
난 바쁘단 말이다! 네놈을 상대할 시간 없어!
I am busy. I have no time to face you!
그치만 말이야, 이 녀석이…
But, this guy…
아까부터 신경쓰였는데… 그 애는 뭐지?
I couldn't help noticing that boy, but who is he?
미아라고 해야 되나…
A missing child?
제법 귀엽게 생긴 소년이군.
He is a cute boy.
하지만, 미아라면 경찰에 맡겨라!
But if he's a missing child, give him to the police!
그러니까, 경찰은 위험하다고!
The problem is that we can't trust the police!
꼭 경찰 아저씨에게 다려다 주렴.
Please take him to the policeman.
알겠나, 엔?!
Understood, En?!
카이 따위에게 부탁한 내가 바보였지!
I was stupid to ask Kai for help!
할 수 없지, 집에 가자.
Well, then. Let's go home.
들어와.
Come in.
미유키, 시끄러워.
Miyuki, shut up.
저녀석, 손님이 오면 꼭 짖어댄다니까.
He always barks when there's a guest.
지금은 부모님이 지방에 가셔서 아무도 없어.
Nobody's home, as my parents are away for now.
사양할 필요 없어.
Don't scruple on your way in.
그치만 너, 우선 샤워 해야겠다.
But first, you should take a shower.
모르는 거 있으면 불러.
Call me if you need help.
야, 온도 어때?
Hey, how's the temperature?
켄타…!
Kenta!
켄타!
엔…
En?
너, 혼자 목욕해 본 적 없어?
Didn't you ever take a shower by yourself?
뭐, 됐어. 기분 좋지?
Well, it doesn't matter. Do you feel good?
응, 기분 좋아.
Yes, it feels good.
그래,  그래.
That's great!
왜 그래?
What's wrong?
배 고파서 그러나?
Is he hungry?
기다려, 맛난 거 만들어 줄게.
Wait for a moment. I'll make you something good.
이거…
This…
라면 싫어해?
Don't you like ramen?
라면…
Ramen?
슬슬 다 됐으려나.
It should be ready by now.
-엔…
-응?
-En.
-Huh?
엔도 라면이 되는구나?
En has become a ramen.
이상한 소리 하지 말고 얼른 먹어.
Don't say such stupid things and eat!
젠장, 꽤 하는군.
Damn, you're good at this!
매일 컵라면 먹어도 괜찮다면 쭉 우리집에 있어도 돼.
If you're good with eating a cup of ramen every day, you're good to stay in my house.
듣고 있어?
Are you listening to me?
저기, 켄타.
Hey, Kenta.
너, 대체 누구야?
Who exactly are you?
맞아!
That's it!
그러니까… 단축…
Speed dial number…
히로세 카이다.
This is Kai Hirose.
헷갈렸다…
Nope, that wasn't it.
여보세요.
Hello?
요쿠냐? 난데…
Is it Yoku? It's me.
너, 인터넷인가 뭔가 한다고 했지?
Do you use the internet or something?
-네...
-잠깐 뭐 좀 알아봐 줄래?
-Yeah.
-Can you find something for me?
켄타라는 아이의 수색 요청이 나와 있는지 말이야.
Check if there's a search request for a boy named Kenta.
유괴일지도 몰라.
It might be a kidnap.
그런 것보다, 제 말 좀 들어보세요.
That aside, please listen to me!
일전의 복제 쥐 말인데요, 같은 DNA를 가진 개체가,
About the rat cloning before, I tried feeding alcohol every day to a rat to find out
환경에 어떻게 반응할지 조사하기 위해 저, 그 중 한마리에게 매일 알콜을 줘 봤습니다.
how the species with DNA will respond to a change in the environment.
그랬더니, 이럴수가…
When I did, it was…
꼴 좋다!
Serves you right!
꼴 좋다…
Serves… you… right…
그래, 해충이니까.
Yeah, it's a pest.
아, 안되지.
Oh, right.
다시 말해, 같은 종의 생물이라도, 또, 같은 조건 하에서 생활하더라도 큰 차이가 있다 이말입니다.
In other words, even for creatures of the same species, and even if they live in same conditions, there are big differences.
실제로 생존력이 부족한 약한 개체도 존재하기 때문에 그 메커니즘은…
In reality, there are creatures with a weaker life force, so their mechanisms are…
과연 그렇군! 잘 알았어!
I see! I understand!
어쨌든 수색 요청 건 부탁할게.
Anyway, please do what I asked!
그치만 아직 제 이야기가 끝나…
But I'm not done with my…
기분 좋아?
Do you feel good?
커다란 목욕탕 기분 좋아?
Do you feel good in that big tub?
장난치는 거야? 저거 바다잖아?
Is he joking? That's a sea!
-바다…?
-바다라구. 가 본 적 없어?
-Sea?
-It's a sea. Have you never been there?
-가 보고 싶어?
-가 보고 싶어.
-Do you want to go?
-I want to go.
좋아, 다음번에 데려가 줄게.
Alright, I'll take you soon.
걱정하지 말라니까.
Don't worry.
녀석들이 습격해 와도.
Even if they come to attack,
내가 지켜줄테니까 말이야.
I'll protect you.
동생이 있었다면 이렇게 했을까?
If I had a brother, would I act like this?
데안도졸이 레벨2를 넘기고 72시간이 경과.
72 hours have passed, and Deandozol has evolved to Level 2.
급히 손을 써야만 해.
I must do something quick.
국문학 담당인 타키자와 선생님이 결근하셔서 오늘은 특별히 내가…
Today, our literature teacher Takizawa is absent, so I'll be specially teaching today…
헤에, 그렇구나 엔 녀석, 지금쯤 미유키란 애와…
Oh, that's it! En must be having a good time with Miyuki!
아이고, 지각이다!
I'm late!
이미 지각이 문제가 아니군.
Oh well, being late isn't a problem anymore.
오늘은 쉰다!
I declare this a day off!
얼레, 켄타 녀석은?
Huh, where's Kenta?
얼레, 이거 뜻밖인걸.
Hey, that's unexpected!
미유키가 남과 친해지다니 말이야.
You became friends with Miyuki?
엔…
En.
꼴 좋다…
Serves you right.
이 바보야!
You idiot!
나 참, 이거 참 잔인하구만.
Hey, that's cruel!
이렇게 함부로 죽이면 불쌍하잖아.
Aren't they pitiful if you kill them like this?
불쌍해…?
Pitiful?
불쌍해…
Pitiful…
뭐, 그렇게 기죽을 필요 없어.
Well, there's no need to be discouraged.
밥이나 먹고 힘내자구!
Let's have breakfast and start our day!
그럼, 뭐라도 사 올게.
I'll come back with some food.
누가 와도 절대 열어주면 안돼.
No matter who comes, do not open the door.
표적이 혼자가 됐다.
The target is now alone.
-초진동 지뢰를 사용할 건가?
-그래, 대장의 허가는 나왔다.
-Are you going to use super oscillation mine?
-Yes. We have permission from our boss.
어서오십시오.
Welcome.
학교 빠져도 되는 거냐?
Is it okay for you to skip school?
너도 마찬가잖아.
Speak for yourself.
엔, 무슨 잘못이라도 했어?
En, did you do something wrong?
너, 미행당하고 있어.
Someone is following you.
-2015엔입니다.
-알았어!
-2015 yen total.
-Thank you.
거스름돈은 맡아둬!
Keep the change!
감사합니다.
Thank you so much.
미유키라…
Miyuki?
어떤 여자인지 일단 봐 둘까?
Lemme see what kind of girl she is.
뭐, 어찌됐든 별로 상관없지만 말이야.
Well, it doesn't really matter anyway.
이게 뭐지?
What's this?
켄타!
Kenta!
미유키…
Miyuki…
엔…
En.
En…
켄타!
Kenta!
다행이야…!
What a relief!
젠장…
Dammit!
잘도 우리집을…!
How dare they mess with my house…
녀석들이 누군지는 모르겠지만 절대 널 넘겨주지 않겠어!
No matter who they are, I will never give you up!
마리아!
Maria!
미유키를 부탁할게.
Take care of Miyuki!
따라와, 켄타.
Come, Kenta.
자, 잠깐! 엔!
Wa- wait! En!
마리아!
Maria!
너도 얼른 거기서 떨어져!
You get away from there right now!
엔~!
En!
게키!
Geki!
어떻게 된 거야? 너희 집이 흔적도 없이 사라지다니!
What happened? How can your house just disappear without a trace?!
설명은 나중에 할게.
I'll explain later.
학교로 가자!
To the school!
그거야 쉽지!
That's easy!
나다.
It's me.
시간이 없다. 레벨 3으로 넘어가기 전에 반드시 처치해라.
There's no time. Process him before he evolves to Level 3.
그래.
Right.
누구냐?!
Who is it?!
역시 라이잖아.
As I expected, you're Rai!
오랜만입니다! 언제 지구에 오셨나요?
It's been a long time! When did you come to Earth?
오, 오랜만입니다.
I- it's been a long time since…
곤란하군... 하필이면 이런 때에…
It's bad… At such a time…
왜 그러세요?
What's wrong?
무슨 문제라도 있어?
Do you have any trouble?
아, 아닙니다.
No, nothing!
그것보다 선배님들, 어떻게 이곳을…
Anyway, senpais, how did you find out?
어떻게냐니…
How?
저런 걸로 날았다간 바로 들킨다구.
Do you think we wouldn't notice that thing?
그, 그렇네…요.
Th- that's right…
비켜 비켜 비켜 비켜 비켜 비켜라!
Move, Move, Move, Move, Move, Move, Move!
풍기위원 제군!
Disciplinary gentlemen!
이상, 말한대로 낙서와 기물 파손을 엄중히 단속하여
From now on, as I said, we must preserve the reconstructed
재건된 신성한 산카이 고등학교의 새 건물을 대대손손 보전해야하지 않겠나!
divine Sankai High School with our hands by protecting it from scribbles and property damages!
우리 풍기위원회의 손으로 말이다!
With our disciplinary members' hands!
무슨 짓이냐?!
What are you doing?!
엔!
En!
어제 전화를 잘못 건 걸 사과하러 왔을…
Are you here to apologize for the wrong call?
…리는 없겠지.
Figures.
엔의 집이 없어졌어.
En's house disappeared.
녀석은 보통 사람이 아니야!
The enemy isn't an ordinary man!
적이다!
It's an enemy!
제군!
Gentlemen!
난 당분간 학교를 비우겠다!
I will be away from the school for a while!
안녕히 다녀오십시오!
Take care!
명왕 위원장!
Pluto Chief!
친한 친구 사이에도 예의가 있다! 지구에 왔으면 먼저 우리에게 인사를 하는 게 도리 아니냐?!
There are manners between close friends! If you're on Earth, you should have said "Hi" to us first!
그건 그렇지만…
That's true, but…
어쨌든 이걸로 다그온 전원 집합이구만.
Anyway, all the Dagwons are gathered because of this!
환영 파티 말인데요 엔의 집에서 할까요?
Should we do a welcome party at En's house?
아, 아니, 그건 좀…
N- no, that's um…
엔의 집이 싫은가요?
Do you hate En's house?
아니오, 그렇지는…
No, that isn't…
너, 우리에게 뭔가 숨기고 있지?
Hey, you're hiding something from us!
그, 그런…! 전 단지 몰래 지구에 관광 왔을 뿐입니다!
N- no way! I silently came to Earth as a tourist!
할 수 없군요.
I'll have to do this.
-신, 꼭 붙들고 계세요.
-어쩔 셈이야?
-Shin, hold him tight.
-What are you going to do?
자백제(自白製)입니다.
It is a drug of confession.
저, 저, 전 절대 극비 임무로 온 게…
I- I'm here for a top secret mission…
극비 임무.
A top secret mission!
이봐, 극비 임무란 게 뭐냐?
Hey, what's that top secret mission?
그건… 극비입니다!
That is top secret!
엔!
En!
야, 기다려!
Hey, wait!
나중에 다시 인사하러 찾아뵙겠습니다!
I'll see you and have a proper greeting later!
-요쿠, 타!
-네!
-Yoku, get on!
-Yes!
젠장! 왜 내가 짐칸이냐구!
Damn, why do I have to ride in the trunk?!
저기, 집은 어디 있니, 켄타 군?
Say, where do you live, Kenta?
아버지는 뭐 하시니?
What does your father do?
확실히 하란 말이야!
Make it clear!
게키! 무슨 속셈이지?!
Geki! What are you thinking?!
왠지 그 꼬맹이를 보고 있으면 화가 나!
I don't know why, but I get angry by looking at him!
한방 먹여주고 싶다구!
I want to hit him!
이런 귀여운 켄타에게 그게 무슨 소리냐?!
What are you saying to this cute boy?!
류 녀석, 아직 안 돌아왔어.
Ryu hasn't come back yet.
미나코도 없어.
Minako's not here either.
적은 어중간한 녀석들이 아닌 것 같아.
The enemy doesn't seem to be mediocre.
여기서 류가 돌아오는 걸 기다리자.
Let's wait for Ryu to come back here.
그래.
Yeah.
하지만 녀석들, 왜 켄타를…?
But why do those guys want Kenta?
신과 요쿠에게도 알리는 편이 좋을지도 몰라.
We'd better let Shin and Yoku know.
그렇군.
Right.
라이… 라이잖아?!
Rai… You're Rai!
오웃, 타이밍 죽이는군!
Good timing!
대체 언제 지구에…?
When did you come back to Earth?
선배, 그 소년을 이쪽으로…
Senpai, hand over that boy.
설마 너, 그녀석들의 동료냐?
It can't be! Are you a comrade of those bastards?!
이유는 뒤로하고, 일단 소년을…
I'll explain it later. Hand over the boy quickly.
레벨 3이다!
It's Level 3!
트라이 다그온.
Try Dagwon!
너 미쳤냐?!
Are you crazy?!
라이, 이자식!
Rai, you bastard!
비켜 주십시오.
Please move.
웃기지 마!
Don't make me laugh!
oshiete hoshii hitomi ni yureru mishiranu hikari wa
教えてほしい 瞳に搖れる 見知らぬ光は
알려주고 싶은 눈동자에 흔들리는 낮선 빛은
I want you to tell me about the strange light swaying to the eye
oshiete hoshii hitomi ni yureru mishiranu hikari wa
namida soretomo yoake no hoshi no kakera
涙それとも 夜明けの星の欠片
눈물, 아니면 새벽의 별 조각일까
Is it a tear, or a fragment of stars upon the dawn
namida soretomo yoake no hoshi no kakera
nazomeku hodo hikareru GEIMU janai ze
謎めくほど魅かれる ゲームじゃないぜ
궁금할 정도로 끌리는 게임이 아니야
It looks like an attractive mystery, not a death game
nazomeku hodo hikareru GEIMU janai ze
kazari no nai kimi ga ii
飾りのない 君がいい
꾸밈없는 네가 좋아
I just like you yourself unadorned
kazari no nai kimi ga ii
wakari takute todoke takute tada mitsumete iru
分かりたくて 届けたくて ただ見つめている
알고 싶어서 닿고 싶어서 단지 바라보고 있어
'Cause I want to know, 'cause I want to reach, I only keep gazing
wakari takute todoke takute tada mitsumete iru
subete kakete mitsumete iru
全てかけて 見つめている
모든걸 걸고 바라보고 있어
I risk everything to keep gazing
subete kakete mitsumete iru
kimi no uchuu ni tadori tsuki tai
君の宇宙に たどり着きたい
너의 우주에 도착하고 싶어
I want to struggle on to arrive in your universe
kimi no uchuu ni tadori tsuki tai
CHANSU wo kurenaika?
チャンスを くれないか?
기회를 주지 않겠어?
Won't you give me a chance?
CHANSU wo kurenai ka
자막 원본: 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103